<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Advice on</title><link>/categories/advice/</link><description>Recent content in Advice on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 16:30:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/advice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Marketing for Techies: Part 2 How to</title><link>/blogs/marketing-for-techies-part-2-how-to/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 16:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/marketing-for-techies-part-2-how-to/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In Hindi, we have a famous saying: &amp;ldquo;Sahi Jagah Pe Dikhega, Tabhi To Bikega&amp;rdquo; which means to sell, you have to make it (it= you, your work/ product) visible at relevant places. Good work/ product doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any value if no one knows about it. Marketing is what gives it exposure to others and makes it valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last atomic essay (no. 3) we saw why it is important to market yourself. In this essay we see different ways to do it:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Data Citizens Should Use AzureML To Embrace AI Adoption Quickly</title><link>/blogs/data-citizens-should-use-azureml-to-embrace-ai-adoption-quickly/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/data-citizens-should-use-azureml-to-embrace-ai-adoption-quickly/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is named a Leader in the 2021 Gartner Magic Quadrant for Cloud AI Developer Services.*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Azure is the cloud computing service created by Microsoft for building, testing, deploying, and managing applications and services. Azure Machine Learning is a fully managed cloud service to build, deploy and share the predictive analytics solution. It provides tools such as AzureML studio to create complete machine learning solutions in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some main differentiators of AzureML that can greatly benefit Data Scientists and Data Citizens:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>You Will Never Use Stackoverflow The Same Way After Reading This</title><link>/blogs/you-will-never-use-stackoverflow-the-same-way-after-reading-this/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/you-will-never-use-stackoverflow-the-same-way-after-reading-this/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Stackoverflow is an indispensable resource but most of the users are under-utilizing the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stackoverflow is more than just a question-answering platform for coders. Apart from helping with code, it provides valuable insights into why something will and will not work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t make the mistake of using Stackoverflow without creating an account. Having an account will give you the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Save Time by Upvoting&lt;/strong&gt;: Upvote questions so next time you face an issue, you will realize that you have been in the same position before. Upvote answers you found useful so you can simply reuse the solution that worked for you in the past. Upvoting also helps the owner of the answer in increasing their reputation and is seen as a reliable solution.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>1 Indispensable Skill Every Data Professional Must Know</title><link>/blogs/1-indispensable-skill-every-data-professional-must-know/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/1-indispensable-skill-every-data-professional-must-know/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;tldr: &lt;strong&gt;SQL&lt;/strong&gt;. There&amp;rsquo;s no surprise. Ask any industry veteran and they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t deny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me try to convince you by showing its importance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Literacy:
Data is an asset. We live in a &amp;ldquo;data-driven&amp;rdquo; world. Business teams must know data literacy to leverage it. The easiest way to get business executives and employees started with it is using SQL. The syntax isn&amp;rsquo;t tough and helps to get started in a short time. Data literacy is no longer &amp;ldquo;nice to have&amp;rdquo; but a &amp;ldquo;must-have&amp;rdquo; skill.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The 3 Problems Beginners Face While Learning Python And How To Solve It</title><link>/blogs/the-3-problems-beginners-face-while-learning-python-and-how-to-solve-it/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/the-3-problems-beginners-face-while-learning-python-and-how-to-solve-it/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I have been working in IT for 7 years. Since starting as a BI Analyst and working my way up to a Data Scientist, I have learned a lot about what it takes to solve some of the biggest problems people face in our industry. I was once a beginner and I know the problems they face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People want to learn Python and excel in their careers. But they are often puzzled which resource to choose and how to proceed. Plethora of options are available; both online and offline. Everyone you ask has their own recommendations. The choice becomes even more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>