<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Azure on</title><link>/categories/azure/</link><description>Recent content in Azure on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 14:30:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Advantages of Using Automated Machine Learning</title><link>/blogs/advantages-of-using-automated-machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/advantages-of-using-automated-machine-learning/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Automated Machine Learning (AutoML) is a configurable wizard that lets you automate the model development part. It lets you focus on the business problem at hand. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to spend days on tuning hyperparameters manually. This can get you up to speed to see your work in action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colleagues who can&amp;rsquo;t code can leverage automl tools, fail fast, and ultimately succeed. Here are some advantages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frees you from the setting up the development environment&lt;/strong&gt;
You can compare the performance of many different Machine Learning algorithms at once. Also, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to install different packages or fight with different interfaces, or data frame formats.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why Use Azure Databricks When We Have AzureML</title><link>/blogs/why-use-azure-databricks-when-we-have-azureml/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/why-use-azure-databricks-when-we-have-azureml/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Databricks is built on top of open-source Apache Spark. Azure Databricks gives you the service within the Azure ecosystem. More suited for Data Scientists who are comfortable with coding in Python, SQL, R, Scala, JAVA, and .NET. It is a fully managed service for streamlined development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are using Azure, you have 2 options to use services like Azure Databricks and Azure Machine Learning for Data Science Workloads. Both these services can integrate with other Azure services. Let us try to understand why we need Azure Databricks when we already have AzureML.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>