<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data Science on</title><link>/tags/data-science/</link><description>Recent content in Data Science on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 16:30:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Machine Learning Monitoring: A Cross-Disciplinary Endeavor</title><link>/blogs/machine-learning-monitoring-a-cross-disciplinary-endeavor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 16:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/machine-learning-monitoring-a-cross-disciplinary-endeavor/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Monitoring is a cross-disciplinary endeavor, meaning that different professionals may have different interpretations of what it entails. For data scientists, it may mean one thing, while for DevOps and business professionals, it may mean another. That&amp;rsquo;s why, when it comes to monitoring, there are several key areas we focus on: incoming data, machine learning models, and serving infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine learning is powerful, but it&amp;rsquo;s not infallible. Machine learning is only as good as the data it&amp;rsquo;s trained on and the environment in which it operates. If you&amp;rsquo;re relying on machine learning models to make decisions, you need to know when those models are no longer accurate. Monitoring can help you catch those issues early.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why it is important to monitor your machine learning systems</title><link>/blogs/why-it-is-important-to-monitor-your-machine-learning-systems/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 16:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/why-it-is-important-to-monitor-your-machine-learning-systems/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s business world, ML algorithms are becoming increasingly integral to crucial decision-making processes. However, it&amp;rsquo;s important to recognize that like any software, these algorithms are not without their flaws. ML models are subject to bugs, errors, and changes in data inputs. Therefore, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to monitor these models to ensure that they remain accurate and effective. Regular monitoring enables businesses to identify issues before they cause significant problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ML monitoring is essentially monitoring the performance of ML models over time. By tracking their performance, businesses can identify areas for improvement and make changes quickly. This gives them an edge in a fast-paced business environment, enabling them to make faster, more informed decisions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AzureML Pipeline Checklist</title><link>/blogs/azureml-pipeline-checklist-v01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 16:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/azureml-pipeline-checklist-v01/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As part of a project, I created a couple of Azure ML pipelines. There were a lot of learnings. I want this cheat sheet to serve as a good reference point. This checklist by any means is not complete and may differ from other projects&amp;rsquo; implementations. I wanted this checklist as a quick note to remind myself of all the common things that are applicable in future projects that I/ others do.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Understanding DevOps from the lens of a Data Scientist</title><link>/blogs/understanding-devops-from-the-lens-of-a-data-scientist/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 16:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/understanding-devops-from-the-lens-of-a-data-scientist/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="need"&gt;Need&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Data Scientist or a Machine Learning Engineer will come across Machine Learning Operations (MLOps) when the model needs to be deployed in production. The principles of MLOps have their roots in the Software Development and IT Operations (aka DevOps) culture. It thus becomes important to understand what DevOps is, to better understand and implement MLOps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="background"&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IT industry has undergone tremendous development in the last couple of decades. There are different roles and job responsibilities within a software development lifecycle. Each team has a dedicated role to play. There can be no progress by isolating one team from the entire process. It thus becomes imperative to understand the contribution of these different teams in the software development lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Azure Service Principal 101: Understanding the Basics for Data Scientists</title><link>/blogs/azure-service-principal-101-understanding-the-basics-for-data-scientists/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 16:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/azure-service-principal-101-understanding-the-basics-for-data-scientists/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="service-principal-in-azure"&gt;Service Principal in Azure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Service Principal (SP) is an identity that is used by applications, services and APIs to access resources in Azure. Its primary use is to authenticate and authorize applications or services access to Azure Resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SP is a secure identity based on Azure Active Directory (AD)-based authentication. SP is associated with a specific Azure AD tenant and can be granted different levels of access to resources within that tenant. You can think of SP as a technical user who is primarily used for tasks such as:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>