<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Programming on</title><link>/tags/programming/</link><description>Recent content in Programming on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 14:30:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Kids Should Learn Programming At An Early Age</title><link>/blogs/why-kids-should-learn-programming-at-an-early-age/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/why-kids-should-learn-programming-at-an-early-age/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Knowing how to code is nothing less than a superpower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It lets one create stuff with minimal resources that can be useful for others. Imagine kids developing this superpower at an early age. They are not discouraged easily and can overcome challenges better than an adult. Their imagination does not know practical limitations. Programming is translating this imagination into building stuff. This stuff can be anything - a robot to play around with, a nice website, solving mathematical problems, creating games, intelligent solutions, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How I Saved Several Hours To Clean Data Using The Terminal Instead Of Python</title><link>/blogs/how-i-saved-several-hours-to-clean-data-using-the-terminal-instead-of-python/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/how-i-saved-several-hours-to-clean-data-using-the-terminal-instead-of-python/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="background"&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few weeks ago at work, I was given a dataset by some business guys. They wanted to find some keywords in specific text columns. The data was huge about ~300MB, approximately 3 million rows, and had about 30 columns delimited by |. Data in a few columns were repeated and as a result, it was introducing redundancy in the dataset. As the data was directly exported by a DBMS to a CSV format, there were some formatting issues as well. Not only the file was huge but the format of the data wasn&amp;rsquo;t ideal to be simply read by pandas for data manipulation. Moreover, opening this file in Excel was a challenge as only the first 1000k rows were being displayed and there was a possibility of truncation of data.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Data Citizens Should Use AzureML To Embrace AI Adoption Quickly</title><link>/blogs/data-citizens-should-use-azureml-to-embrace-ai-adoption-quickly/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/data-citizens-should-use-azureml-to-embrace-ai-adoption-quickly/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is named a Leader in the 2021 Gartner Magic Quadrant for Cloud AI Developer Services.*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Azure is the cloud computing service created by Microsoft for building, testing, deploying, and managing applications and services. Azure Machine Learning is a fully managed cloud service to build, deploy and share the predictive analytics solution. It provides tools such as AzureML studio to create complete machine learning solutions in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some main differentiators of AzureML that can greatly benefit Data Scientists and Data Citizens:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>You Will Never Use Stackoverflow The Same Way After Reading This</title><link>/blogs/you-will-never-use-stackoverflow-the-same-way-after-reading-this/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/you-will-never-use-stackoverflow-the-same-way-after-reading-this/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Stackoverflow is an indispensable resource but most of the users are under-utilizing the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stackoverflow is more than just a question-answering platform for coders. Apart from helping with code, it provides valuable insights into why something will and will not work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t make the mistake of using Stackoverflow without creating an account. Having an account will give you the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Save Time by Upvoting&lt;/strong&gt;: Upvote questions so next time you face an issue, you will realize that you have been in the same position before. Upvote answers you found useful so you can simply reuse the solution that worked for you in the past. Upvoting also helps the owner of the answer in increasing their reputation and is seen as a reliable solution.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>No-Code and Code Solutions will Continue To Coexist. Here's Why:</title><link>/blogs/no-code-and-code-solutions-will-continue-to-coexist-heres-why/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/no-code-and-code-solutions-will-continue-to-coexist-heres-why/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The No-Code offerings are gaining momentum but it is equally important to understand the shortcomings associated with their use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A no-code solution enables users to make use of drag-and-drop components without coding to build a software app. In the last couple of years, no-code solutions have gained a lot of momentum. Popular examples include bubble.io, Airtable, etc. There are quite a few advantages of using no-code approaches over coding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rapid Prototyping&lt;/strong&gt;: Have an idea and want to create a Minimum Viable Project (MVP)? No-code solutions should be your go-to choice.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PyScript: Run Python In The Browser and Say Goodbye To JavaScript</title><link>/blogs/pyscript-run-python-in-the-browser-and-say-goodbye-to-javascript/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/pyscript-run-python-in-the-browser-and-say-goodbye-to-javascript/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;PyScript was announced at PyCon 2022 by the director of Anaconda Inc., Perter Wang. Here&amp;rsquo;s are some quick bytes about it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-pyscript"&gt;What is PyScript?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using PyScript, you will be able to run python code within HTML. Its goal is to combine several technologies that help build sophisticated and elegant UI applications in the browser. Currently, PyScript supports running popular packages such as numpy, pandas, scikit-learn, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-problem-is-pyscript-solving"&gt;What problem is PyScript solving?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before PyScript, Python developers were required to learn JavaScript for web applications. Now Python developers can feel native to web apps and develop their apps with python itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>5 Reasons Why Python Should Be Your First Programming Language</title><link>/blogs/5-reasons-why-python-should-be-your-first-programming-language/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/5-reasons-why-python-should-be-your-first-programming-language/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Python is a great programming language for beginners. It is suitable for people of all educational backgrounds. It is simple to use and easy to understand. There are abundant resources to seek help if you get stuck somewhere. Here are some reasons to choose Python as your first programming language:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="community"&gt;Community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python has probably the largest community of users. Developers from all around the world use it in their day-to-day job for various purposes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>5 Reasons Why Writing Pythonic Code Is Crucial</title><link>/blogs/5-reasons-why-writing-pythonic-code-is-crucial/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/5-reasons-why-writing-pythonic-code-is-crucial/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia defines Pythonic code as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;Pythonic code may use Python idioms well, be natural or show fluency in the language, or conform with Python's minimalist philosophy and emphasis on readability.&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets see why you should write Pythonic code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easy Maintenance: When it comes to writing faster and scalable architecture code, we should strive to leverage pythonic code. Using pythonic code, we can use the libraries more efficiently. Multi-threading, hyper-threading becomes easy&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>