<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on</title><link>/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 14:30:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Business Users Can Learn Python In Their Busy Schedule</title><link>/blogs/how-business-users-can-learn-python-in-their-busy-schedule/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/how-business-users-can-learn-python-in-their-busy-schedule/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Business Users can benefit a lot if they know how to use python. They not only learn a new skill but technically are not blocked from finding answers from data. Data is the new oil and having someone who can make sense of it is a great addition to the organization. Here are some ways in which Business Users can learn python:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just learn enough basics&lt;/strong&gt;
As a business user, you may not be required to learn concepts like Object Oriented Programming, Decorators, etc. Simply understanding how a python script runs, writing functions, installing packages, and solving common errors is enough to get started. The rest of the things can be picked up when you are progressing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Practical Tips To Improve Readability and Quality Of Your Python Code</title><link>/blogs/practical-tips-to-improve-readability-and-quality-of-your-python-code/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/practical-tips-to-improve-readability-and-quality-of-your-python-code/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Readable code is a sign of professionalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t get better if you are doing the same things over and over again. To get better, we must stretch from our comfort zone, and learn and implement what is missing in our knowledge gap. Here are some ways that help you write better code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read PEP-8&lt;/strong&gt;
It is a set of official python recommendations and guidelines to improve the readability of your python code. It contains guidelines on naming conventions, indentations, layout, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PyScript: Run Python In The Browser and Say Goodbye To JavaScript</title><link>/blogs/pyscript-run-python-in-the-browser-and-say-goodbye-to-javascript/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/pyscript-run-python-in-the-browser-and-say-goodbye-to-javascript/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;PyScript was announced at PyCon 2022 by the director of Anaconda Inc., Perter Wang. Here&amp;rsquo;s are some quick bytes about it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-pyscript"&gt;What is PyScript?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using PyScript, you will be able to run python code within HTML. Its goal is to combine several technologies that help build sophisticated and elegant UI applications in the browser. Currently, PyScript supports running popular packages such as numpy, pandas, scikit-learn, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-problem-is-pyscript-solving"&gt;What problem is PyScript solving?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before PyScript, Python developers were required to learn JavaScript for web applications. Now Python developers can feel native to web apps and develop their apps with python itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>5 Reasons Why Python Should Be Your First Programming Language</title><link>/blogs/5-reasons-why-python-should-be-your-first-programming-language/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/5-reasons-why-python-should-be-your-first-programming-language/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Python is a great programming language for beginners. It is suitable for people of all educational backgrounds. It is simple to use and easy to understand. There are abundant resources to seek help if you get stuck somewhere. Here are some reasons to choose Python as your first programming language:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="community"&gt;Community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python has probably the largest community of users. Developers from all around the world use it in their day-to-day job for various purposes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>5 Reasons Why Writing Pythonic Code Is Crucial</title><link>/blogs/5-reasons-why-writing-pythonic-code-is-crucial/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/5-reasons-why-writing-pythonic-code-is-crucial/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia defines Pythonic code as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;Pythonic code may use Python idioms well, be natural or show fluency in the language, or conform with Python's minimalist philosophy and emphasis on readability.&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets see why you should write Pythonic code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easy Maintenance: When it comes to writing faster and scalable architecture code, we should strive to leverage pythonic code. Using pythonic code, we can use the libraries more efficiently. Multi-threading, hyper-threading becomes easy&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The 3 Problems Beginners Face While Learning Python And How To Solve It</title><link>/blogs/the-3-problems-beginners-face-while-learning-python-and-how-to-solve-it/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/the-3-problems-beginners-face-while-learning-python-and-how-to-solve-it/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I have been working in IT for 7 years. Since starting as a BI Analyst and working my way up to a Data Scientist, I have learned a lot about what it takes to solve some of the biggest problems people face in our industry. I was once a beginner and I know the problems they face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People want to learn Python and excel in their careers. But they are often puzzled which resource to choose and how to proceed. Plethora of options are available; both online and offline. Everyone you ask has their own recommendations. The choice becomes even more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>