<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Self-Help on</title><link>/categories/self-help/</link><description>Recent content in Self-Help on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 14:30:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/self-help/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How To Overcome Thoughts That Are Holding You Back</title><link>/blogs/how-to-overcome-thoughts-that-are-holding-you-back/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/how-to-overcome-thoughts-that-are-holding-you-back/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It is important to observe your self-talk. Often in these talks, you can see patterns in your thoughts. The patterns of self-limiting beliefs, lies and the half-truths that you tell yourself. Such misbeliefs can be a strong reason that is holding you back and not allowing you to reach your goals and true potential. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how you can address these:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask where do these misbeliefs start?&lt;/strong&gt; Was it some first-hand experience that had an impact on you? Did you listen to someone else&amp;rsquo;s advice and it didn&amp;rsquo;t turn out what you expected? Find the root cause and try to address the issue. Take a pen and paper to mind-dump the issue, its root cause and what can you do to overcome such misbeliefs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why Kids Should Learn Programming At An Early Age</title><link>/blogs/why-kids-should-learn-programming-at-an-early-age/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 14:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blogs/why-kids-should-learn-programming-at-an-early-age/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Knowing how to code is nothing less than a superpower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It lets one create stuff with minimal resources that can be useful for others. Imagine kids developing this superpower at an early age. They are not discouraged easily and can overcome challenges better than an adult. Their imagination does not know practical limitations. Programming is translating this imagination into building stuff. This stuff can be anything - a robot to play around with, a nice website, solving mathematical problems, creating games, intelligent solutions, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>